[music]
>> Hello. Wow, full room. This is so good
to see. Welcome everybody. This is open
source in the age of AI. I'm so excited
to have everybody here and let's start
by saying hello to our guests. So, we
have here with us today Guido van
Rossum. Sorry, Guido van Rossum.
>> [laughter]
>> Uh Samuel Colvin.
Hi there.
Sebastian Ramirez.
>> Hello. And Jeremiah. Everybody. I mean,
come on. They they deserve claps.
>> [applause]
>> Very good. So, I'm going to start then
I'm going to let you introduce
yourselves like super quick. Do you want
to just do
a quick round of introductions? What are
you doing right now?
Who are you?
Jeremiah, do you feel like you go first?
>> Um I just introduced myself to about
half of this room in my talk. So, for
the other half, um I'm Jeremiah. I'm the
CEO and founder at Prefect. I'm the
author of Fast MCP.
Um my open source career is about two
decades long at this point, always in ML
data and some kind of photonic interface
and it's amazing to be here.
Thank you. Uh Sebastian? Hey, I'm
Sebastian Ramirez or Tiangolo. I created
Fast API and a bunch of other projects.
Now I'm creating Yeah, now I'm creating
[clears throat]
I'm building Fast API Cloud with a bunch
of very cool people that I have some
here.
That's pretty much it.
Hi everyone. I'm Samuel. Uh
I originally created Pydantic. Uh now I
run Pydantic the company and thanks to
AI it is now trendy again for CEOs to
write code. So, I'm allowed to well, at
least pretend Claude's the right code uh
if not actually write very much of it
myself. Although actually secretly I do
actually write it, but I get to say
that's cool because that's the that's
trendy again.
>> [laughter]
>> All right.
Same for me actually.
Uh
I'm probably twice as old as the average
of the three of you. [laughter]
I represent the older generation. I
didn't do anything with AI, didn't
invent it, but I invented a language
that's apparently seems to steer a lot
of it.
So, I think I haven't seen a single
example that wasn't in Python so far.
Which is good cuz this is a Python
conference.
>> [laughter]
>> So, we're safe, everybody. We're safe.
Very good.
Uh so, you were
I'm going to start with you then with
the questions because I think everybody
wants to hear a little bit more from
you.
Um okay, so
you
created Python. Yes, you mentioned.
>> [snorts]
>> Um you stepped back from the benevolent
dictator for life role after the
walrus operator situation. Mhm. Um and
it's been a while now. So, do you want
to tell everybody what you've been
working on? How's life? What are you
doing? Uh I'm still part-time employed
basically because it pays for my medical
uh
insurance.
Uh I'm at Microsoft. I Well, first for 4
years I worked with a team of five or
six people on making CPython faster.
That was a fantastic time.
Uh
I
sort of grew out of that project
and then since since a year and a half
or so, I've been noodling around with AI
without really understanding [music]
what I'm doing, but
many of the talks that I've seen so far
resonate very much.
We're all doing the same thing
basically.
Um perfect. Uh so, I heard you were
working on a
project called Type Agent.
Right? Uh yes, that's that's what I
meant with noodling around. Okay.
[laughter]
And and what does it do? Uh
it is supposed to be
the the core engine for long-term agent
memory.
And the the agent is fed messages that
could be you just chatting with a model
about anything really or together
building something.
Every interaction gets fed into the
agent. The agent doesn't just store the
text with for later retrieval using rag.
Instead, the agent actually sends the
interaction to a model which extracts
knowledge. It It sort of
finds key
activities
entities, people, things, act
concepts.
And those extracted entities are stored
together with the raw text in a
database. We then query the database not
through rag, but just by looking for
entities with specific properties or
names or what have you.
Facets.
Uh
and then sort of the database the out
output of the database query is fed to a
model that turns it into a nice to the
the user's original question. Okay,
nice. And I saw I mean, actually Samuel
told me that you've been using Pydantic
AI and Pydantic Cloud API.
>> [laughter]
>> So, I mean
>> Yeah, a little bit.
I was quickly sold on Pydantic for
anything that needed to be serialized.
And we have some requirement that we
want to be able to serialize everything
that's in the database in a SQL
independent form.
So, that's that's where we use Pydantic
and then most recently
with help of Claude uh we converted the
entire code base
>> [snorts]
>> so that
instead of having hardcoded support for
OpenAI and Azure OpenAI
and Azure separately mostly because all
the off is different.
Uh
now
retaining the the Azure off support
uh we can use Pydantic AI's naming
scheme for provider colon model.
Uh and very glad I I waited I had wanted
that for a long time, but I had to wait
until there was also embedding support.
And the day that the embedding support
landed, I started looking at this for
real.
Nice. Yeah, he actually told me this
over dinner last night. So, you know,
I'm biased.
Uh do you want to say anything about it?
Um we have plenty to discuss. So, if you
don't
>> Let's move on. Let's move on. Awesome.
Perfect. So, we are now then going to
talk a little bit about problems.
Um
I've been worried
with the situation
um with AI slop. I don't know if Sweex
is here, but if he is, no more slop.
It's a really good chat to have.
Um
but the situation with the Matplotlib
maintainer
um that was shamed by a an autonomous
bot uh from having its PR closed, uh the
curl
uh bounty program being closed as well
due to AI slopiness being submitted.
It It worries me
because well,
open source is based on this gift
economy
um and we need to
keep the door open so that the gifts
come back.
Um I've seen I know that Fast API and
CPython have some policies put in place
for AI sloppiness.
Um
but in most recently, GitHub also
decided to roll out a feature where you
can basically
close the ability to have PRs open on
your repository.
Um we all know this is a problem.
Uh we're kind of tired of, you know,
discussing the problem.
Um so, I'm going to look at each one of
you as very powerful people in the open
source and I would like to hear
solutions. So,
>> [laughter]
>> I'll go first. Great.
Thank you.
>> GitHub has a massive opportunity to help
the open source community and if they
don't, there is an enormous opportunity
to supplant GitHub. They need to have
human and AI identity. It is not going
to be perfect. It is not going to work
out of the box. You can't simply say
people using the web interface are
humans and people using the CLI or the
API are bots because there are there are
contradictions, but like I think you
could get an awful long way with
uh both an honesty-based system of is
this human or is this AI? And then with
using AI to detect when that's not the
case. And then with reputation on people
so that if you you you basically have a
metric on you on on your GitHub profile
which is how sloppy is the code you
submit. Sloppy in the sense of like, you
know, the those big PRs that come in.
Look, I will say that
Monty, which I'm going to talk about
later, is arguably a slop fork of
CPython.
Um that is not true
because it's not a fork.
Uh the slop bit has has some truth to
it. I'll explain why that is. Uh do come
to my talk, but I think that there is
enormous opportunity for for like
AI-generated code. The problem is when
people are submitting stuff which is
which they are claiming They basically
they generate loads of code, they send
it to me, they expect me to go and read
this like 10,000 lines of code they
haven't read. So, the obvious where
place we want to get to is you can
submit AI generated code if you either
tell me it is all AI generated or have
read it yourself and think it is right.
As in, you don't expect someone else to
be the first person to to read your
code. And I think that GitHub can make
that happen, they just need to pull
their finger out and think about how to
make it happen.
Okay, thank you for that.
Um
good. Um who would like to go next?
I'm going to wait. Well,
uh
So So, how do you follow that? Um
I I think I think it's helpful to like
subset the problem a little bit. So, I
don't think it's just AI, right? If AI
is not allowed to make PRs, then every
PR I've made in the last 2 years
is can't work. It's really when we're
getting such a volume of AI submitted
PRs that are not conducive to the
project. And that's really tough. Um
I
I also think it's not necessarily a new
skill though, right? Open source
maintainers have always had to find ways
to say no. It's been really important to
sort of protect the project. Um it's
really the problem is that it used to be
that opening the PR was the hurdle, the
the friction to participation and it was
hard to do. So, you didn't get PRs
except for someone who was deeply
motivated to contribute and then you can
have a nice conversation. Now, the cost
of opening the PR has gone to zero and
so I think that's really where I think
about this. Um
I wrote a blog post that
was momentarily viral last fall called
an open source maintainers guide to
saying no and in it I just tried to
explore
what can one actually do from a process
standpoint short of waiting for GitHub
wants to solve this problem for us,
that's great. What can one do from a
process standpoint? We tried some things
on the fastMCP repo, we tried requiring
an issue to be opened before a PR could
be opened. Uh what happened is the issue
would be opened 1 second before the PR
would be open. We tried saying you need
to interact with a maintainer. I just
moved the burden to the issues page
instead of to the PR page. Um
I think at some point the most effective
thing we did is we said PRs will be
closed if they're too long. If the
description is too long because LLMs
have this weird insistence on telling
you everything they did even though the
code is right there. Um that actually
has been the most effective thing. It's
a heuristic, it's not a rule, it will be
dead in 3 months, but one of the best
things we did is we created like a I
think it's like too long is the label.
And we just slap it on a PR that's just
too long. If it took you that long,
there's something is too long
description
>> Literally too long description. Yeah,
not code. Okay. 10,000 lines of code
with a five-line description, I'll dig
it.
>> [laughter]
>> But a 10,000 line description for five
lines of code and you're out.
And that's been a heuristic that's
actually working and
I don't know that's as close as I have
to a solution is like how do we just
move the process? What I'd love to do is
short of an AI detection system
Do you remember there were these
proposals for stopping spam in email by
making a computer like do a little
microsecond like computation before it
sent a message and the idea was you
couldn't send 10,000 messages cuz you'd
have to pay this tax, this non-monetary
tax. I would love to find a constructive
friction to introduce into the PR
process, not so onerous that it would
deter any person who's pouring
disproportionately more time into
actually solving a problem in the code
but enough to deter just like this wrote
sloppiness.
Okay. Sebastian, you've dealt with way
too many issues and pull requests for
years.
Is it Is it getting worse or are you
just like more of the same? Way worse.
Just don't don't tell your open cloud
thingies to write small descriptions
because we are screwed then.
>> Yeah, then we're done. That's the only
thing we have. Yeah, I think you know
like I think uh
a good thing to think about is that the
it becomes a problem of at the
distributed denial of service of
maintainer attention, time and effort.
When
a bunch of people can put a bunch of
bots
to say like, "Hey, go and check this
repository and find like any issue or
any discussion and make a PR to solve
whatever it is that they said." The
effort that that person has to make is
tiny. And then this creates a PR that
will consume days of reviewing. And then
it's just like the imbalance of the
effort needed for that is just crazy.
And then it's just like, you know, like
it's putting maintainers to consume CPU
cycles like crazy. And this is, you
know, like it becomes a denial of
service attack that is not intentional,
you know, like it's like of course we're
all trying to help and it's like, "Okay,
maybe I could use this new tool to
help." But when it's easier for the
maintainer to go and write the same
prompt and see what is the output,
that's actually going to be a lot easier
to review, to handle happens than
reviewing uh you know, like a thousand
line
code PR. Also, because there's also like
the this additional thing that is not
necessarily too spoken about and this
the the security that if I write a
prompt and I make the thing create a
long PR, I know that at least it was
whatever was output from the LLM. But if
someone submits a PR, I don't have any
certainty that it was actually just
generated by an LLM. If someone could
send a very long PR and then like, you
know, sneak in some uh
crypto mining something or I don't know.
And like, you know, like
I have to review each PR super
thoroughly independent of who wrote it.
So, you know, like it's like this
imbalance of effort that makes things
super super difficult. There was the
There's a good documentary about the XZ
vulnerability that nearly got introduced
to Debian where the code that they used
to go and
whatever it was, basically inject their
own password into OpenSSH was encoded in
a binary blob of data that they were
saying was an example of compression.
So, it was it was a compression library,
so you have all these random blobs that
you demonstrate the compression is
working for and they had the code inside
that binary blob, so no one would notice
it. And like
And And one of the things I say in that
documentary is
it is weird how few
supply chain attacks we've discovered,
e.g. Probably there are more, we just
haven't found yet. And
It would I've been like waiting for it
to happen for years. I've had some
issues where where I have refused to
accept PRs because the I won't go into
the details publicly, but like there
were just too many smells and it's very
hard to say, "Look, you have don't have
a suitable public profile and that's and
what you're doing is scary enough, I
won't merge it." But like you kind of
got to. And I still think we're waiting
for the real supply chain. Maybe if XZ
had been let loose, it would have
actually been good cuz it would have
been a Yeah, it might have knocked out
entire health care systems, but it would
have reset us all and realized we need
new answers to this. But then what's the
weight of the policy in that? I think I
think we need this like federated
reputation thing where you can use up a
bit of reputation when you submit a PR
and you get a bit back when it gets
merged. And like that reputation, I
don't want it to live only with one big
company, but maybe it's better for it to
live with Microsoft e.g. GitHub than no
one. But it would be best if it was
federated, but then if you're every time
you submit a like 10,000 line PR, you
use up a little bit of your reputation,
you get it back when it's merged. Now,
I'm I get that profile on when I'm
reviewing a PR, that's that's the like
it's a start, right? The new economy of
open source. I think it's I think it's
interesting and but I also think it ties
into I think I think as maintainers we
also have an obligation to bring people
into open source, right? I I hope folks
here, especially at this is a Python
conference, I hope folks here are
contributing to open source
to some degree. It's a really wonderful
thing. Um it's a chance to learn a lot.
I can think of in the projects that I've
I guess been apprenticed to as a as a
more junior maintainer, I got to I got
to watch amazing people cultivate open
source communities. I learned a lot from
that. And so I think one of the
challenges to solve in any of these
frictions that we introduce
constructively is we have to make sure
that we still have a path
for folks to come into open source, so
it doesn't devolve into
you know, credential credentialism,
right? And it's almost like a credit
score. It's like you build your you
build credit on a certain credit card
and then maybe I worry
>> Now, you can contribute to fastAPI. I
worry a bit about putting a gate on that
though.
Um
>> [snorts]
>> one of the beauties of open source is
that it's open for everybody. Yes. So,
we have in Pydantic, we have this thing
we call big cheese where we basically
have a Chrome extension that inserts a
summary of who someone is and where they
work and it gives them a brutal one to
five score on how valuable they might be
as a customer. I know it sounds
offensive, but we did it because we had
an issue submitted on Pydantic by one of
the OpenAI founders and we
one of us was critical of it and closed
it. And after that we were like, "Okay,
we can't carry on doing this." And so we
have this thing that inserted, but it is
pure credentialism because we don't have
the means to go and do a like
how good is this person's code, but you
could imagine that could exist. But then
beginners. I'm sorry, you you would like
to wait a minute. Uh well, yeah, I've
been listening to this. Uh CPython is
a very big, very well-known project.
We try to put sort of barriers in place.
Like we we also require an issue for
every PR except for typos.
And we don't actually like PRs that fix
typos.
>> [laughter]
>> Unless the typos are particularly sort
of in your face when you're reading the
docs. But typos in a comment, we just
close that usually. Mhm. And so we've
seen over the past couple decades so
many different ways that people
try to sort of sneak a PR in
to Python in the hope that it gets
accepted
uh so that they can put on their little
resume Python contributor.
>> [laughter]
>> No, seriously, that that that seems to
be very often
What [laughter] happened?
I fixed a typo.
So,
AI isn't not isn't even all that
different. We get plenty of PRs that are
not AI generated and are also annoying.
Like just
people opens the new new issue form, uh
doesn't fill out any of the fields and
hit commit or submit. Yeah.
Fortunately, those are easy for the
triagers and and and we are fortunate to
have a large community of triagers and
core devs who do the triages together
and those people have a lot of
experience in in sort of catching all
kinds of abusive PRs.
And yeah, they had to think about what
are we going to do about about AI and
there's sort of a policy that's forming
where we say, well, it's okay to use AI
tools.
It's not okay to
submit a PR that has no sign of a human
actually being involved.
Uh
this
usually appears very quickly when we ask
a question about a PR like, why did you
do this? Or
what does this actually do?
There's no response.
And then we label it as pending and
after 2 weeks we close it.
It's a it's mostly a manual process as
far as I know, but
You see, that's a really good hook for
our next question.
Which is about code reviews.
Um
well, we have
AI tools producing code. It's Can I jump
on the previous question just for a
second? Uh sure. I mean, of course. Um
one thing that I am doing that I think
like it's something that can be adopted
by everyone contributing is uh of course
I use I a bunch of AI to do a lot of the
work. Now, when I make a PR to another
project uh I I you know, like I
I started writing long descriptions
before AI that was
the thing. You know, like
before I was the hipster like that. But
then now I write a section where when I
open a PR I write a section with an AI
disclaimer saying I use this model or
this combination of models. Here's the
full prompt and the full discussion.
Normally in an HTML details so that it
doesn't render right away. You can just
like click it and then you can read the
whole thing. What was my whole
conversation with the LLM thing.
And the other thing is the the switching
perspective of like my intention is not
to be a contributor to this thing to say
like, I am a contributor now because
like I made the LLM do something. I want
the problem to be solved. I want the
thing to be solved. So it's like, look,
this is what I did. This is the prompts
and the things that I used. It's quite
probable that it will be better for you
just to replicate what I did and create
another PR and just do it.
And that's totally fine by me. I don't
need my PR to be accepted. I want this
problem to be solved. This is how I'm
approaching it and I'm just like opening
the full disclaimer of this is what I
used. This is what I did. So it's like
easier for the person to say like, what
is it that I'm actually reviewing? What
is the human input in this? What what is
the this person asking to solve? How did
this person wanted to solve the thing?
And the code becomes second.
>> I I wouldn't click on that button. I
would just I would just read
your personal description of why you
wanted, why you needed. Of course, you
have some reputation so you don't have
to worry that you're mistaken for a
spammer.
Uh and then I would just read the code
and if the code is overwhelming I I sort
of I'll put it off. I and I will be
super happy about it. You know, like I
will be glad like, okay, you know, like
this is this is just
bringing attention to like this thing
that maybe could be done. And I will be
completely fine and like actually happy
if you just like write the prompt
yourself and probably do it slightly
different with a lot of extra context
that you have
and figure out how how to solve it. If
sorry, Eliza, I'm carrying on on the
previous subject.
>> It's it's okay. We have a little bit of
time. Go. Uh I think if if we if we
accept the like slightly currently
slightly hyperbolic take that Python and
dare I say TypeScript and Rust are
becoming the intermediate representation
and it's now the like markdown
description or the plan that is the
high-level language.
We're not we're definitely not in a
place like some of those
AI companies are claiming where like all
that we have is the like description,
the spec and then like the code is
ephemeral. We definitely want to keep
that code because it's it's not like
generating assembly from C or where you
can where you can do it completely
repeatedly, but like
you can imagine you get to the point
where your pull request is actually just
the plan. And then you let the you let
the maintainer or
or you know, GitHub go and run that and
now we have a
defensible okay, well, this was the plan
and then this is what we got out and so
we know at least that it like
if you read the plan that it has at
least tried to do the honorable thing. I
I will say I love when I get a
well-scoped issue that I can send one of
my agents with my skills, with my
preference to just go implement that
plan. That will get merged so much
faster than a giant PR that I have to go
review and put myself in a different
head So then it's the shift from
creating the code to creating the plan
and reviewing the plan. Because my next
question is actually going to be how do
you review 10,000 lines of code if, you
know, you're the human the human behind
the screen actually looking at that?
I have an answer, but I don't want to
dominate.
As someone who has merged from some
10,000 line PRs,
so there there are like four rules I
think where
where if these are where if these are
met, AI accelerates you by like 10 or
20x rather than 3 or 5x. And they are
um the internals of the implementation
are kind of known to the model. It's in
its soul, in its weights. The external
interface is known by the models. You
don't have to explain it.
The unit tests either exist or are easy
to generate and there's no bike shedding
about what that interface is because it
already exists. So you think about
people building like clones of Redis,
which which is a kind of like almost a
meme at this point. All four of those
rules are met and so you can go and
produce a clone of Redis that would have
taken a good engineer years before in a
matter of hours now because all of the
unit tests it just doesn't do the same
thing as Redis. It knows what the
interface to Redis is. You don't have to
bike shed about what the messages are.
You know exactly what they need to be.
And that's why Monty is possible is
because those four rules apply. Guido
and others have gone and developed this
like wonderful language that I'm just
going and
making a slightly different take on, but
I don't need to work out the semantics
or the the interface. And so I think if
those if you one of the other things is
if you have those rules, then you can
have these enormous PRs where you can
have an AI review them and then merge
them without reading the code because
it's fully tested and the interface is
not disputed.
But those are those are the exception
not the rule of of code.
But
not all security vulnerabilities can be
catched by
doing that.
True.
Uh So if there is a blast radius still.
So how do we how do we keep humans being
relevant on reviewing
PRs with 10, 20, 50,000 lines of code? I
would much rather
sort of co-develop that PR
from small beginnings
with
occasionally bursts of code written by a
model, but carefully reviewed then.
Uh so that
that the the typical mistakes that the
models make like, oh, they like to clean
up the code surrounding where they're
rooting around and now the PR is much
bigger because there's all this
irrelevant clean up or re-indentation or
whatever happening.
Uh
And if you if you actually work with
another person who
who is a real contributor and you you
sort of develop it together.
You don't have to be pair programming.
But [clears throat]
sort of a back and forth between two
humans leads in my view in case in a
case like Python
uh which is intentionally moving rather
slowly
uh
leads to
to much better
sort of sanity in the project than
accepting 10,000 PRs that whether
whether those 10,000 lines were written
by a human
who did a couple of all-nighters
or by an AI
doesn't even matter so much.
That if someone confronts you with
10,000 lines of code
I find it real hard to believe that
that those are the right 10,000 lines of
code. But see, Python is
>> And and and I think these people all
would would much more easily believe
that
because they they think about
using using the tools themselves. Yeah.
But I'm I'm
sort of old-fashioned for for something
as important as Python where if we screw
up
we we introduce a
a bug into everybody's systems.
>> Yes, 100%. But
you know,
not everybody is CPython.
Um so um Yeah. then focusing on well, we
have smaller projects. We have projects
that need to move fast. Then how do we
do that? How do we make code review
um relevant, effective, good for
projects that need to move much faster
than CPython?
Any takers? I mean, I I think I think
it's
it's very tempting to keep using the
10,000 line as the epitome of what's
wrong.
But
>> [clears throat]
>> the truth is most PRs are five lines of
code, 20 lines of code, whatever they
are. Maybe generated by an LLM, maybe
not. And I think they still take up as
much mental burden to review. And so I
really think it's about
>> [snorts]
>> whether it's an LLM or not. And like
genuinely not caring for a second. I
think it's about creating an environment
where explaining the code is of
paramount importance. Right? Just if the
description is clear and the code is six
lines of code, then I will take the time
to review it and it will go in. And it's
about I think it's about a mutual trying
to reduce the burden, which is which is
not new in open source. It's just that
we've so tipped the scale on where you
can get an advantage, which is in the
code production now. Um and so I think
when you see Look, if someone if someone
has their LLM write me a little
description on a little [clears throat]
PR, wonderful, great. I don't care that
it's an LLM. The code is the code at the
end of the day. I don't care who wrote
it. I've We're not going to
discriminate.
It's when it takes a disproportionate
burden. So I think it's about frankly
just creating that culture and it's a
conversation and it's it's why I think
open source and community kind of go
hand in hand to some degree and it's a
little tougher with with LLMs of what it
means to to have a community, right? So
um
uh a really clear agents.md or claw.md
or your readme changes a little bit in
the age of AI. You're you're you're
trying to find ways to sort of create
the um
the conventions by which your repo
operates and I'm sure it's everyone's is
different, right? Mine is different than
what I agree, but I also think I mean
we're not talk None of us are talking
about the like bleeding edge of what it
looks like to build an AI, right? Open
clause, I think Armin told me 1.4
million lines of code written by written
in a matter of months. That is like some
imagine massively more than CPython.
Like it's a very different league that
they're in in terms of you know you can
think of league and good or league and
bad, but like or you can just think of
it as completely different thing that
they're doing, but like it's a very very
different take to Pydantic or FastAPI or
FastMCP or or CPython or any of the
stuff we're doing and I think
I don't know if I had a particular point
there other than that like there are
people doing far more crazy things. They
don't have any backward compatibility
requirements.
>> No. No, no, no. If if their changes
tomorrow or next week or in 2 weeks,
nobody cares. And they're almost
embracing it's insecure by design. I
mean that's sort of the point, right?
It's like yeah, it can do everything on
your machine so there's no such thing as
security.
It is Well, it's effectively Peter's
take, right?
>> Its objective is to be a kitchen sink.
Yeah.
>> And so a lot of the things that I think
would defend a PR a technically good PR
may get rejected from a project that is
human curated because it's not
it doesn't comply with the ethos of the
project, right? Doesn't advance the
project's goals even if it's good code.
I don't know if I hope that's not a
controversial thing to say. I got yelled
at once on Hacker News for saying that.
Um big surprise.
>> [laughter]
>> But that but I think that
these these large projects, you know,
part of their part of what they're
trying to do is just absorb every piece
of functionality. Yeah. And you give
over to that. Now I don't it doesn't
I don't know. I build very horizontal
frameworks. I guess we all do up here,
but but
but it's different building a horizontal
framework that is an abstraction's
horizontal than doing something that
isn't in its implementation's horizontal
and I think that's where the other
million lines of code come from, maybe.
Yep. Okay, cool. So, next cuz we're
almost at time.
>> Oh, sorry. And this is Oh, please don't
apologize. We're all having fun. It's
all good.
But I really want to ask this question.
Um well, Python is
fundamental to AI. It's foundational.
Um in your opinion,
how should uh companies, large
companies,
um
that offer LLMs invest back in open
source?
They could do what Anthropic did. They
donated a million and a half dollars to
uh [applause] the PSF.
So money is one answer, indeed. Well,
yeah. Because that money mostly goes to
security uh
developers and researchers so that
we can ensure that Python is secure in
the places that don't just
show in the code base, but also in the
whole ecosystem around it.
Which is impacting
important
I I have to mention the pledge um set up
by by Sentry originally where companies
agree to donate $2,000 per year per
engineer to open source. I think Prefect
member we are. I think strongly
encourage companies to do it. There is
no scale at which $2,000 per engineer uh
isn't possible if you have the right
mindset, but mostly today it is startups
doing it. If the Googles or the I'm
looking at Jason OpenAI got involved. I
introduced Jason to the pledge the other
day so he's fighting the good fight, but
like if big companies went and did that,
that could make a profound profound
difference.
Um
so that's one that's one part of it.
They can also go buy products like
Logfire built by great open source or
open source maintainers. No. Is it Is it
a
slight ad. [snorts] Go on. Um I think
that I think companies just have an
obligation to
uh subsidize the most expensive parts of
open source, which is which is sometimes
money, but more often is like time and
space and meetups and food and things
like that. Um
if anyone here wants to ever come visit
the uh wonderful tech scene of
Washington, D.C. where I live,
uh we we one of the things that we've
done is we've we've taken Prefect's
conference facilities and and
everything. We've just opened it up to
any any Python or data open source
meetup in the city. They can come, they
can reserve our spot. We'll we'll get
the food, we'll give them the space,
we'll take care of it. And it's just
like that's the sort of thing. I
remember when I was organizing meetups,
that was the worst finding a place and
finding food. It just it doesn't take
much. It takes a couple of pizzas,
right? It's not it's not crazy, but
there's logistics, there's overhead,
there's coordination and um
>> security Yeah, so yeah, exactly.
>> Yeah, we we used to have things like
that at Google. Google hosted early Bay
Piggies meetings in Silicon Valley for
years.
And eventually they stopped because
they wouldn't let strangers in their
building after hours anymore. That that
was just like the security the physical
security team was too uncomfortable with
that. Yeah, that that was the end. There
are conflicts.
There are tensions, but there are little
things like that or
sponsor the the the the pledge is
wonderful. We try to give our team some
budget that they can
donate to open source projects that they
use or don't use or like or don't like
whatever for whatever cause just at
their discretion. Just being involved in
creating a healthy community, I think is
And Sebastian, do you want to say your
final remarks? I have 8 seconds.
>> [laughter]
>> And then make the most of it. I I
totally say
No, I totally agree that money helps a
lot because money buys time and effort
from the people that need to do the
work. It sounds I don't know too
commercial or something, but it's really
important. Uh in many cases, something
that I think is not thought about a lot
is
regulations and the way laws are written
and the way lawyers think about things
is very
uh enclosed and very anti-open source
and lawyers don't know about open source
and it's super weird, but you know like
standard [snorts]
startup tech California laws whatever
are very restrictive of No, if you if
you write any character of code, it
belongs to the company, you cannot do
open source and it's super limiting. And
uh just because people are just like
abiding by whatever the lawyer told
them, like they normally just like
follow along and say okay, you cannot
just like do open source because like we
will get in a problem and we will have
to talk to lawyers and we don't want to
do that. Uh
but if there was anything anyone that
has like any connections with lawyers
that could figure out a way to make it
easier to do, that would actually be
super helpful because for companies will
be much much cheaper to get like one day
a week for a few of their employees work
on the open source tools that they are
using than waiting for those tools to go
stale and deprecated and having to do a
massive migration that is going to break
production. So like you know like being
able to find the different ways to just
like inject support to the systems. I
think that would be helpful. Talk to
Mozilla. They have open source
knowledgeable lawyers and have had them
for 25 years.
>> point Nice. Thank you.
>> I'm I'm I'm surprised to hear this
actually because that was the state of
the art like around the turn of the
century. Yeah.
I fight with my lawyers so much. I
thought it got much better.
But
Yeah, is it in Germany or here? No,
here, here. Interesting. Okay, we're at
time. I am so sorry to interrupt this
lovely discussion, but thank you so much
and that's it. Well, contribute to open
source everybody. No more slop. No more
slop. No more slop.